Guide to the John Wendel Dodds Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
John Wendel Dodds papers
1942-1967
SC0139
Dodds, John W. (John Wendell), 1902-
3.75 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Biographical/Historical note
Professor of English at Stanford (1937-1967; emeritus 1967- ), interim head of the Department of French and Italian (September 1972-April 1973), Dean of the School of Humanities and Director of Special Programs in the Humanities.
Scope and Contents note
The majority of these files date from Dr. Dodd's term as Dean of the School of Humanities and Director of Special Programs in the Humanities. Also included are miscellaneous files created during his service on various University committees, including one on Far Eastern Studies; files and film footage from two programs written and narrated by Dodds and filmed by KQED (public television station, San Francisco): AMERICAN MEMOIR and THE MEASURE OF MAN; and the published version of AMERICAN MEMOIR, 1961.
Access Terms
Dodds, John W. (John Wendell), 1902-; Rockefeller Foundation; Sokol, Anthony Eugene.; Stanford University. School of Humanities and Sciences.; Stanford University. Special Programs in Humanities.; American memoir.; East Asia.; Motion pictures.; The Measure of man.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Anthropology, Viking Fund Budget (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Anthropology Conference (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Anthropology Viking Fund Cultural Grant (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Area Courses (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Deans’ Meetings (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Donors Prospective (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Graphic Art (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Graphic Art (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - History (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Humanities, School of Description (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Independent Study (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Intensive Foreign Language Courses (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Philosophy (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - President corres. With (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Publicity (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Rockefeller Grant (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Rockefeller Report, 1943/44, etc. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - State Dept., U.S. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Suggestions by Individual Council Members (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Summer Quarter (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Teacher Training (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Academic Council—Executive Committee (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Audio-Visual Aids Committee (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Behavioral Sciences (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Curriculum Committee (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Ford Foundation (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Graves, Arnold (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Hispanic American Studies (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Hoover Library Project (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Humanities and Sciences, School of (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Humanities and Sciences, School of—Executive Committee (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Humanities Council (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Humanities Film Committee (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Humanities, Special Programs in—Annual Reports to the President 1954/55 – 1964/65 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - “Know Your Stanford” (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Liberal Education II (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Pacific and Asiatic Studies Committee (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Social Science Research Council (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Social Thought and Institutions (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Summer Quarter, 1948-1966 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - TV—Educational (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Dodds, John W. American Memoir. New York: Holt, Rinehart Winston, 1961. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Directory of the Stanford University Faculty Classified according to (1) familiarity with geographical areas (2) fields of special competence. Prepared by the Committee on University Services, April 1943 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Stanford University faculty lists with foreign specialties, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Visiting faculty list, summer 1953 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Pamphlet: Stanford University Announces a Program of Pacific-Asiatic-Russian Studies, ca. 1946 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Sub-committee on Far Eastern Studies, minutes and memoranda, 1951-53 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Far Eastern Studies, assorted memos, ca. 1953-54 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Far Eastern Studies, correspondence with other materials, 1942-45 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Far Eastern Studies, correspondence with other materials, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Sokol, Anthony, Asiatic and Slavic Studies, correspondence and memos, 1949-54 (Box 5, Folder 9)